Most people use Claude by typing in a chat window.
I built a runtime around it.
367 lines of legacy Flask code.
SQL injection. MD5 passwords.
Admin routes with zero auth.
This is what I'm refactoring —
without breaking anything.
Here's what that looks like.
Before touching a single line —
A pre-flight check.
33 automated verifications.
9 slash commands verified.
State DB ready. 0 failures.
Claude reads the entire legacy codebase.
Every smell gets catalogued
into a SQLite state database.
Not in a chat.
In a structured state machine
with 7 tables and typed fields.
Each phase has an exit gate.
Claude cannot move forward
until every criterion is met.
No hallucinated progress.
No skipped steps.
Gate validated. Phase locked.
Every session updates a dashboard.
State is committed to git.
Human-readable SQL dump.
Every decision. Every smell. Every metric.
No black box.
7 phases · 9 slash commands
SQLite state · Gate validation · Context budget
Built with Claude Code.
↓ Repo in the comments